Now, most of the code that you've written has been synchronous, and
你所写的大部分代码都是同步的
this means that each line of code gets executed one right after another.
意思是每行代码都是一个接着一个执行
And you must wait for each line to finish executing before going on to
必须等待一行代码执行了 再转到下一行
the next line, but recently we've been learning about asynchronous callbacks.
但最近 我们学习了异步回调
And this means that we tell the system we're interested in a certain event,
意思是我们告诉系统 我们对某个事件感兴趣
like a click event, and then tell the system to notify us,
例如点击事件 然后告诉系统当该事件发生时
or call us back when that event happens.
要通知我们或来回调我们
And in the meantime, we can go do something else in the app, and
在此期间 我们可以在应用中执行其他操作
that means we're not sitting around stalled or waiting for
也就是我们并没有干坐着 等着用户
the user to click on the button on the screen.
点击屏幕上的按钮
And when the event happens, or if it even happens at all, then
当该事件发生时 或者有机会发生的话
the system will call us back and we can execute instructions that we specified.
系统将回调我们 我们可以执行我们指定的说明
So the on click listener callback and the list views
所以 onClickListener 回调和列表视图
on I don't click listener callback were both examples of asynchronous callbacks.
OnItemClickListener 回调都是异步回调
So for example, we only want to play the audio file for each word when the system
例如 只有在系统回调我们并告诉我们特定列表项被点击时
calls us back and tells us that a certain list item was clicked on.
我们才希望播放每个单词的音频文件
This means that in that time while we're waiting, we can still do other things
意味着在等待期间 我们依然可以执行其他操作
like scroll the list, or wait for other user input events.
例如滚动列表 或者等待其他用户输入事件
So doing something while we're waiting for an event to happen and
执行某些操作 并等待某个事件的发生
then jumping back into action is called an asynchronous callback.
然后再回去执行操作这一过程就称为异步回调
And so for sure you might sometimes hear it called async callbacks.
有时候你也会听到 Async Callback 这一说法
So A-S-Y-N-C, async callback.
A-S-Y-N-C Async Callback
Now, as you learn more about Android development,
当你越来越熟悉 Android 开发
you will realize that async callbacks are a common pattern in Android for
你将发现异步回调在 Android 中是个常见模式
us to set up listeners for events on the device.
使我们能够对设备上的事件设置监听器
And so, for example, there are listeners for when the user's location changes.
例如 有一种监听用户位置变化的监听器
Now in order for your app to behave as a user expects, you need to be able to
为了使你的应用能按照用户的预期执行操作
hook into these and be able to handle those cases properly.
你需要能够利用这些异步同步 并正确处理这些情形
Now, let's learn more about another callback.
我们再来详细了解下另一个异步回调
So the media player API offers several so
MediaPlayer API 提供了几个回调方法
that developers can get notified when certain events happen.
这样当特定的事件发生时 开发者能够获得通知
Specifically, there's a callback that tells us when an audio or
例如 当音频或媒体文件完成播放时
media file has finished playing.
会有一个回调告诉我们这一情况
Can you search online to figure out which callback method that is?
你能去网上搜索 并找出该回调方法是什么吗？
And write that answer in this box when you find it.
找到后 请将答案写在这个方框中
When you found that answer,
找到答案后
I like to use that information to modify the sample music player app.
请你使用该信息修改示例 MusicPlayer 应用
So change the app so
对该应用做出更改
that when a song is done playing, it pops up a toast message saying I'm done.
当歌曲停止播放时 应用会弹出提示消息“I'm done!”
Now this step can be a little bit tricky, so
这一步会有点难
take note of the hints that we provided you down below this quiz.
请参考练习题下面提供的提示